<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>PowerShell on dacarab&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://dacarab.github.io/tags/powershell/</link>
    <description>Recent content in PowerShell on dacarab&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2021 00:42:04 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dacarab.github.io/tags/powershell/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Pulling Text from a PDF</title>
      <link>https://dacarab.github.io/posts/2021/02/pulling-text-from-a-pdf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2021 00:42:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dacarab.github.io/posts/2021/02/pulling-text-from-a-pdf/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the last article, we started to look at the iText 7 library, and how to use NuGet to install it and it&amp;rsquo;s dependencies. In this article, we&amp;rsquo;ll start to look at the classes that we need to leverage in order to start interacting with the PDF file, and pulling out the data that we are interested in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to understand how to  extract text from a PDF, we are going to need to use a mixture of the iText7 libraries&#39; model of a PDF, as well as an understanding of elements of the PDF format itself. In other words, we&amp;rsquo;ll be able to use iText7 to &amp;ldquo;get at&amp;rdquo; the text data of the PDF - but it&amp;rsquo;s not going to be in plain text, it&amp;rsquo;s going to be formatted as per the PDF standard. So once we have that PDF formatted data, we are going to need to manipulate this data in order to extract the text contained within the PDF document. This will make more sense if we walk through an example.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extracting Data From a PDF Report</title>
      <link>https://dacarab.github.io/posts/2021/02/extracting-data-from-a-pdf-report/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2021 14:14:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dacarab.github.io/posts/2021/02/extracting-data-from-a-pdf-report/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There are often times when you are provided information in a report format that you need to do something with. For example, you may receive a regular report from your internal Security team that lists a set of missing patches or security vulnerabilities across your server estate, and you need to action the items listed. These reports are often produced in PDF format.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trying to manually pull information out of a report like this and turn it into a useable structure can be tedious and error prone - so having the ability to extract and structure the relevant information from the report, and use one or more scripts to then do something with it, can be very handy.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
