<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2021/02 on dacarab&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://dacarab.github.io/posts/2021/02/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2021/02 on dacarab&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language><atom:link href="https://dacarab.github.io/posts/2021/02/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Pulling Text from a PDF</title>
      <link>https://dacarab.github.io/posts/2021/02/pulling-text-from-a-pdf/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2021 00:42:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dacarab.github.io/posts/2021/02/pulling-text-from-a-pdf/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the last article, we started to look at the iText 7 library, and how to use NuGet to install it and it&amp;rsquo;s dependencies. In this article, we&amp;rsquo;ll start to look at the classes that we need to leverage in order to start interacting with the PDF file, and pulling out the data that we are interested in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to understand how to  extract text from a PDF, we are going to need to use a mixture of the iText7 libraries&#39; model of a PDF, as well as an understanding of elements of the PDF format itself. In other words, we&amp;rsquo;ll be able to use iText7 to &amp;ldquo;get at&amp;rdquo; the text data of the PDF - but it&amp;rsquo;s not going to be in plain text, it&amp;rsquo;s going to be formatted as per the PDF standard. So once we have that PDF formatted data, we are going to need to manipulate it in order to extract the text contained within the PDF document. This will make more sense if we walk through an example.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Extracting Data From a PDF Report</title>
      <link>https://dacarab.github.io/posts/2021/02/extracting-data-from-a-pdf-report/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2021 14:14:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dacarab.github.io/posts/2021/02/extracting-data-from-a-pdf-report/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There are often times when you are provided information in a report format that you need to do something with. For example, you may receive a regular report from your internal Security team that lists a set of missing patches or security vulnerabilities across your server estate, and you need to action the items listed. These reports are often produced in PDF format.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trying to manually pull information out of a report like this and turn it into a useable structure can be tedious and error prone - so having the ability to extract and structure the relevant information from the report, and use one or more scripts to then do something with it, can be very handy.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuring Packer to Use an Answer File</title>
      <link>https://dacarab.github.io/posts/2021/02/configuring-packer-to-use-an-answer-file/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2021 10:53:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dacarab.github.io/posts/2021/02/configuring-packer-to-use-an-answer-file/</guid>
      <description>In Part 10 of this series, we walked through the additional configuration that needs to be added to the sample Windows answer file that we have been extending, in order to enable setup to install the Paravirtual storage driver.
We are stepping away from the answer file now, to add some of the final touches to our Packer template file. Now that we have a Windows answer file in place, we can reference it from Packer, as well as set the WinRM credentials that will be needed to automate the build of our Windows 2019 vSphere template.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuring Driver Paths within the Windows Answer File</title>
      <link>https://dacarab.github.io/posts/2021/02/configuring-driver-paths-within-the-windows-answer-file/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2021 10:09:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dacarab.github.io/posts/2021/02/configuring-driver-paths-within-the-windows-answer-file/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dacarab.github.io/posts/2021/02/defining-the-windows-edition-to-install/&#34;&gt;Last time&lt;/a&gt;, we looked at how to go about choosing the appropriate Windows edition image from within the WIM image on the installation media, and defining this in the answer file that we are working with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this article, we finish off our answer file configuration by adding the necessary settings to point to the locations of the Paravirtual Storage and network drivers that will be required by Windows setup.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Defining the Windows Edition to Install</title>
      <link>https://dacarab.github.io/posts/2021/02/defining-the-windows-edition-to-install/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2021 12:16:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dacarab.github.io/posts/2021/02/defining-the-windows-edition-to-install/</guid>
      <description>Previously, we covered adding additional configuration to our Windows answer file that defined the Administrator password, auto logon and time zone settings on our template VM.
In this article, we continue to build out our answer file by covering how to identify the necessary information from the Windows installation media to select the edition of Windows that we want to install, and then adding this info to the appropriate section of the Windows answer file.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
