<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>2021/01 on dacarab&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://dacarab.github.io/posts/2021/01/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 2021/01 on dacarab&#39;s blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language><atom:link href="https://dacarab.github.io/posts/2021/01/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Configuring a Windows Answer File for use with Packer</title>
      <link>https://dacarab.github.io/posts/2021/01/configuring-a-windows-answer-file-for-use-with-packer/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2021 17:08:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dacarab.github.io/posts/2021/01/configuring-a-windows-answer-file-for-use-with-packer/</guid>
      <description>In the previous article we discussed the high level changes that we need to make to the sample answer file that comes with the Windows Server installation media, with a view to tailoring it for use with the Packer template file that we are working on.
In this article, we&amp;rsquo;re going to start to add that configuration by making the necessary changes to the FirstLogonCommands section of the answer file.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating a Windows Answer File for Use With Packer</title>
      <link>https://dacarab.github.io/posts/2021/01/creating-a-windows-answer-file-for-use-with-packer/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 15:33:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dacarab.github.io/posts/2021/01/creating-a-windows-answer-file-for-use-with-packer/</guid>
      <description>In this article, we will cover the initial creation of a Windows answer file, which will be used as part of the Packer template file that we have been putting together in previous articles in this series. Future articles will discuss the additional configuration that will need to be added to this file as we tailor it to our requirements.
This answer file will automate the initial setup a Windows Server 2019 VM template in a vSphere 7 environment, which Packer will then customise to meet our needs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Provisioning Installation Files With Packer</title>
      <link>https://dacarab.github.io/posts/2021/01/provisioning-installation-files-with-packer/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 15:25:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dacarab.github.io/posts/2021/01/provisioning-installation-files-with-packer/</guid>
      <description>In the previous article, we added the necessary configuration to our Packer template that defines the storage and network adapters that are presented to the VM template machine.
In this article, we will further expand on our Packer template by configuring the windows installation media as well as presenting the necessary drivers to Windows OS at install time. In a future article, we&amp;rsquo;ll cover off the configuration within the Windows answer file that is needed to point windows setup to the location of these driver files.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuring our VM Template With Virtual Devices Using Packer</title>
      <link>https://dacarab.github.io/posts/2021/01/configuring-our-vm-template-with-virtual-devices-using-packer/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 15:23:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dacarab.github.io/posts/2021/01/configuring-our-vm-template-with-virtual-devices-using-packer/</guid>
      <description>Previously, we started to look at adding OS agnostic virtual resources for the vSphere VM template to use.
Next, we&amp;rsquo;ll look at further expanding on the Packer template that we are building up by adding virtual devices that the operating system will interactive directly, and will thus require device drivers for.
Defining the template OS In order to be able to utilise the storage resources that we&amp;rsquo;ve defined, we need to define a virtual storage card - this will look like a piece of hardware to the template machine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuring VM Template Hardware With Packer</title>
      <link>https://dacarab.github.io/posts/2021/01/configuring-vm-template-hardware-with-packer/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 15:20:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dacarab.github.io/posts/2021/01/configuring-vm-template-hardware-with-packer/</guid>
      <description>In Part 2 of this series, we discussed how to utilise the vsphere-iso Packer builder component in order to connect up to a vSphere 7 environment.
In this article, we will continue to expand on that template, and introduce configuration to define the virtual hardware to allocate to the template VM machine.
Adding additional vSphere settings To start with, we&amp;rsquo;ll create User Variables for the cluster, datacentre, datastore and vm folder that it will be deployed to, along with the relevant fields within the vsphere-iso builder:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Connecting to VSphere With Packer</title>
      <link>https://dacarab.github.io/posts/2021/01/connecting-to-vsphere-with-packer/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 15:17:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dacarab.github.io/posts/2021/01/connecting-to-vsphere-with-packer/</guid>
      <description>In the first article in this series, we had an initial look at Packer and the high level components that it employs to automate the creation of VM templates for various cloud and hypervisor platforms.
This time, we&amp;rsquo;ll start to look at some specific configuration to enable us to connect up to a vSphere 7 environment, with a view to automating the creation of a Windows Server 2019 VM template.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automating VSphere 7 VM Templates With Packer</title>
      <link>https://dacarab.github.io/posts/2021/01/automating-vsphere-7-vm-templates-with-packer/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 15:09:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dacarab.github.io/posts/2021/01/automating-vsphere-7-vm-templates-with-packer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this article, we&amp;rsquo;ll have an initial look at Packer, briefly discuss the high level components that make up Packer, and have a quick look at the format of an empty Packer Template.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://packer.io&#34;&gt;Packer&lt;/a&gt; is one of a number of automation tools created by HashiCorp. It is used to automate the creation of virtual machine templates, for use on one or more virtualisation or cloud platforms. These templates can then be used to provision server environments.
​​&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
